事无裨益  罚人于身
We are condemned to useless labor.
第四层地狱
Fourth circle of hell.
撇开这些名诗雅句
Charting goes a lot faster
写病历能快很多
when you eliminate all classic poetry.
拾人牙慧  却只为无人问津
Writing down what we already know to be read by nobody.
相信但丁也会认同这些事毫无裨益
I'm sure Dante would agree that qualifies as useless.
你有两个多星期的病历没有补了
You're over two weeks behind in your charting.
哎呀  偏了
Oops. I missed.
你多大  8岁吗
What are you, eight?
8岁小孩能做这个吗
Could an eight-year-old do this?
省省吧  不然就变不回去了
Better stop or it'll stick that way.
你的病人在一号诊室
You have a patient in exam one.
你看  我12点下班  现在都5点了
Yeah, see I'm--I'm off at 12:00,and it's already five of.
她11点就开始等你了
She's been waiting for you since 11:00.
万念俱灰啊
Melancholy without hope.
那是第几层呢
Which circle is that?
你好  我是豪斯医生
Hi. I'm Dr. House.
有什么不适吗
What seems to be the problem?
奥古斯丁  给他看你的手
Show him your hands, Augustine.
看着像皮肤红斑
It looks like stigmata.
安静  派尔斯
Shuh Pius
你一定光顾着在圣水冷却器边高谈阔论了
You must be all the talk around the holy water cooler.
最近常洗盘子吗
Been washing a lot of dishes recently?
我在厨房帮忙
I help out in the kitchen.
厨房有新用具吗
Anything new in the kitchen?
这周有人捐赠了平底锅和壶
We just got a donation of saucepans and pots this week.
我打开包装清洗了一下
I unpacked and washed them.
你的双手可是用来拯救灵魂的
Should've spent your time saving souls.
杂活这事儿倒是难了
It's easier on the hands.
接触性皮炎  你对清洗皂过敏
This is contact dermatitis. You're allergic to dish soap.
胡说
Nonsense.
我们一直用的同样的肥皂
We've always used that soap.
怎么现在才出问题呢
Why is there a problem now?
我做医生很多年了
I've been a doctor for years.
为什么一直要向人保证说
Why do I have to keep assuring people
我清楚我做的事情
that I know what I'm doing
人们可能对长期
A person can become allergic to substances
持续接触的物品过敏
that they've had repeated and prolonged exposure to.
好消息是  免费试用装
The good news is, free samples.
苯海拉明  抗组胺药
Diphenhydramine. It's an antihistamine.
能阻断过敏反应
It'll stop the allergic reaction.
每8小时服一片
Take one every eight hours.
可能会觉得有点儿嗜睡
It might make you feel a little sleepy.
再拿些非处方的可的松软膏
And get some of that over-the-counter cortisone cream.
-谢谢你  医生  -要水吗
- Thank you, Doctor. - You want some water?
我带了茶水
I have some tea.
行  休息几分钟就好
Well, you just relax for a few minutes.
药物起效很快
That stuff works pretty fast.
还是过了12点
Still out by 12:00.
你怎么处理像皮炎之类的问题
How do you solve a problem like dermatitis?
-什么  -医生
- What? - Doctor?
感谢你的耐心
I want to thank you for your patience.
她在对你说吗
Is she talkin' to you?
不知道  她绝对是看着我说的
I don't know.She's certainly looking at me.
很高兴得到一个非宗教的诊断
Oh, it's good to get a secular diagnosis.
修女们试图
The sisters tend to
将疾病理解为神的干涉
interpret their illnesses as divine intervention.
你不这样想吗
And you don't?
你也带了个滑稽的帽子
I mean, you're wearing an awfully funny hat.
天  失陪
Ooh, boy. Excuse me
要是我的腿断了  我相信是有原因的
If I break my leg,I believe it happened for a reason.
我相信是上帝的安排
I believe God wanted me to break my leg.
我也相信是他要我打上石膏
I also believe he wants me to put a cast on it.
医生  有些不对
Doctor? Something's wrong.
抬起下巴
Lift up your chin.
修女  你哮喘发作  请你放松
Sister, you're having an asthma attack. I need you to relax.
请卷起她的袖子  我要给你注射肾上腺素
Roll up her sleeve, please. Gonna give you epinephrine.
打开你的肺  帮助你呼吸
Open your lungs to help you breathe.
发生什么事了
What happened?
-她吃药了吗  -吃了
- She take the pill? - Yes.
可能是过敏反应
It was probably an allergic reaction.
她对抗过敏药过敏吗
She's allergic to an anti-allergy medicine?
你觉得是冥冥中的力量要抓走她吗
You figure somebody's out to get her?
-感觉如何  -好多了
- How are you feeling? - Better.
我会换成类固醇药物
I'll put you on some steroids instead
我是不是应该觉得心脏不适
Is my heart supposed to be feeling so funny?
肾上腺素会加快你的心跳
It's called adrenaline.Makes your heart beat fast.
但没这么快  请找个护士来
But not this fast. Get a nurse, please.
躺下
Lay down, come on.
谁来帮帮我们
Help! Somebody help us!
快来人
Somebody get in here!
心肺复苏急救  除颤器充电
Call a code and charge up the defibrillator.
她没有脉搏了
She's got no pulse.
你诊断病症为过敏
You diagnosed the patient with allergies
开了抗组胺药
and prescribed antihistamine.
随后出现呼吸窘迫
She went into respiratory distress.
然后你给她注射了肾上腺素
And you injected her with epinephrine.
估计用了1毫升
Presumable one cc.
0.1毫升  标准用量
Point-one cc. That is the standard dose,
这是我给她的用量
that is what I gave her.
0.1毫升肾上腺素
People don't go into cardiac arrest
不会导致心脏骤停
from point-one cc epinephrine.
她的心脏一定有过往病史
She must have a pre-existing heart
肾上腺素使之恶化
condition that got exacerbated by the epinephrine.
不幸的是没有病历记录
It's too bad you didn't make a notation in the chart.
我现在就能补上
I can make it up right now.
放注射器的抽屉里两种剂量都有
The drawer has syringes is with both dosages,
很容易就会拿错
you could've easily reached for the wrong...
-但是我没有  -谁都会犯错
- But I didn't. - Everyone makes mistakes.
这就是为什么要强制医生
This is why doctors pay through the nose
买医疗事故保险
for malpractice insurance.
放轻松  她们不会起诉的
Relax, they're not gonna sue.
她们最多就是拿戒尺打我的手
Worst they'd do is whack my hand with a ruler.
那纪律委员会呢
And the discipline board,
也会打打手完事吗
are they gonna whack your hand too?
-你打算上报吗  -我有选择吗
- You're gonna report me? - What choice do I have?
不上报怎样
How about not report me?
我只能留她观察24小时
I can justify keeping her here for a 24-hour observation.
要是到时候你找不到心脏停跳的原因
If you haven't found an underlying cause for the cardiac
我只得通知我们的律师
arrest by then, I will have to notify our attorneys.
双手红肿
Her hands were red and swollen.
可能是皮肤感染  蜂窝组织炎
Maybe she has a skin infection, cellulitis?
会有心动过速症状
That could manifest with tachycardia.
没有发热症状
There's no history of fever.
全血细胞计数未显示感染
Results from the CBC didn't indicate an infection.
嗜酸性粒细胞略微增加
The eosinophil were mildly elevated.
血细胞沉降些许上升
Sed rates up a bit.
可能是全身过敏反应吗
Could we be looking at a systemic allergic response?
不是过敏
It's no allergic, and
过敏不会这样导致心脏停跳
allergies don't cause cardiac arrest like this.
-可能是血管炎症吗  -脉管炎吗
- Could be inflammation of the blood vessels. - Vasculitis?
脉管炎不会导致嗜酸性粒细胞增加
That wouldn't give you an elevated eosinophil count.
变应性肉芽肿性血管炎可以
Churg Strauss Vasculitis would.
心脏  肺部
Blood vessels of the heart, lungs,
和皮肤血管炎症反应
and skin become inflamed,
导致哮喘  发疹和心脏问题
causing the asthma, rash, and heart problems.
-解释了全部症状  -需要活检确诊
- Covers all her symptoms. - Need a biopsy to diagnose.
胸部断层扫面更快
Chest CT would be quicker.
她可是因皮疹就医的
The lady just came in with a rash.
这是什么玩意儿
What the hell are those?
糖果棒
Candy canes.
糖果棒吗[圣经典故]
Candy canes?
你在嘲笑我吗
Are you mocking me?
不  圣诞节了  我想
No, I-it's Christmas, and I, I thought
放轻松  逗你玩呢
Relax. It was a joke.
变应性肉芽肿性血管炎的愈后很差
Isn't the prognosis for Churg Strauss a bit grim?
是  不治疗的话  一年存活率仅33%
Yeah. Untreated, only 33% of patients survive past a year,
治疗的话存活率是5年
treated, five years.
那么我绝对支持治疗
Then I definitely suggest treatment.
如果是另一个主治医生
If it was any other attending doctor,
我会说他犯了错误
I'd say that he made a mistake
用了过量肾上腺素
and gave her too much epinephrine.
这么说  你不是在说是我错了
Saying you wouldn't say it was my mistake.
就是  确实是我的错咯
Saying it was my mistake.
可是你说的  每个人都会犯错
Everyone screws up. Your rule.
我觉得你也是大家中的一员
I think you fit within the subset of everyone
我没弄错
I didn't screw up.
预约胸部断层扫描  给修女用强的松
Order a chest CT and start the sister on Prednisone.
40毫克  每日三次
40 milligrams, TID.
修女
The sister?
我没说吗  病人是修女
Oh, didn't I mention? Patient's a nun.
奥古斯丁修女
Sister Augustine.
我讨厌修女
I hate nuns.
谁不讨厌呢
Who doesn't?
奥古斯丁修女吗
Sister Augustine?
我们没看
We weren't watching.
我们只是试试这个是不是床的遥控器
We were trying to see if this is the bed control.
这个是床的遥控器  那个是电视的
Oh, um, this one's the bed control. And that's the TV control.
我是卡梅隆医生
I'm Dr. Cameron.
这是奇斯医生和福曼医生
This is Dr. Chase and Dr. Forman.
我都20多年没看电视了
I haven't seen television in over 20 years.
你们觉得它是魔鬼的产物
Do you consider it the work of the Devil,
还是住处没有安装有线呢
or do you just not get cable where you live?
感觉好些了吗  修女
How are you feeling, Sister?
吃过药  觉得好点了
I seem to be a little better. They gave me some medication.
强的松  类固醇类药物可以消除炎症反应
Prednisone. It's a steroid to help with the inflammation.
豪斯医生诊断出我的病症了吗
Has Dr. House figured out what I have?
会好吗
Will I be okay?
我们还不能确诊
We're not sure what's wrong yet.
今天下午  安排了胸部断层扫描
You'll have a chest CT scan this afternoon
来帮助我们诊断
that'll help the diagnosis.
药都用了
Dr. House was giving her medication,
豪斯医生却还没搞清是什么病吗
and he doesn't know what she has yet?
要相信  派尔斯修女  一切皆有因果
Trust, Sister Pious. It all happens for a reason.
他不清楚自己在做什么
He doesn't know what he's doing.
唯一的问题
The only problem that woman has is
就是豪斯拿错了注射器
that House grabbed the wrong syringe.
你不相信他吗
You don't trust him?
我不信任一个不承认自己会犯错的人
I don't trust a man who won't admit he might be wrong.
你不是也没急着告诉她可能
I notice you weren't so quick to tell her
患有变应性肉芽肿性血管炎
she's got Churg Strauss
没几年好活了
and only has a couple of years to live.
确诊前我不会告诉病人坏消息
I don't tell patients bad news unless it's conclusive.
因为你知道他可能错了
Because you know he might be wrong.
变应性肉芽肿性血管炎有待商榷
About Churg Strauss,
门诊上应该没出什么错
not about what happened in the clinic.
奇斯  你怎么想
What about you, Chase?
也觉得他不会犯错吗
You think he's infallible too?
我知道的是  要是豪斯没错
All I know is, if House didn't make a mistake,
奥古斯丁修女患变应性肉芽肿性血管炎
and Sister Augustine has Churg Strauss,
他会沾沾自喜
he'll be self-satisfied,
而我们能过上几周好日子
and our lives will be good for a few weeks.
要是豪斯错了
If House did make a mistake,
他会不爽  我们就要倒霉几个月
he'll be upset and our lives will be miserable for months.
说到点子上了
There is that.
卡迪要是觉得是我的过失
If Cuddy thinks I made a mistake,
至少也应该停掉我门诊的工作
the least she could do is suspend me from clinic duty.
她不会混淆犯错和失职
She doesn't confuse making a mistake with being incompetent.
又来了  说教时间
Oh, here we go. Lesson time.
我认为自信不是我的缺点
I recognize that confidence is not my short suit.
我还认为我是凡人  可能犯错
I also recognize that I am human and capable of error.
那么  是你搞砸了
So you might've screwed this up?
不是
No.
那么这仅仅是理论上的可能
So it's merely a theoretical capacity for error.
说得好
Good point.
或许没有错误  或许是我的错误
Maybe there isn't one. Maybe that's my error.
要知道  多数和你一样
You know, most people
只考虑自己的人
who think as much of themselves as you do
喜欢谈论自己
like to talk about themselves.
多数人  不爱听
Most people don't like to listen.
你哪儿不舒服
So what's wrong with you?
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
肠炎
Inflammatory bowel.
是  味道那么重吗
Wow, yeah. Is it that bad?
确实
Yes.
病历上也这么说
It's also written on your chart.
血性腹泻  胀气  疼痛
Bloody diarrhea, gas, pain.
磺胺类  无效
Took sulfasalazine, but it didn't work.
接着试了类固醇灌肠剂
Next tried steroid enemas,
口服皮质类固醇  乙酰水杨酸  6-巯基嘌呤
oral corticosteroids, 5ASA, 6-mercaptopurine.
-我给镇住了  -被我的用药史吗
- I'm impressed. - By my medical history?
被上一个医生的完美病历
By how well your last doctor charted.
每个小时去趟洗手间并不是大问题
It's one thing to have to go to the bathroom every hour,
但要是有小孩坐在腿上  这...
but when the kids sit on my lap, it's...
商店会让我回家  他们会炒了我的
The store sent me home. They're gonna fire me.
不能给我开点儿乙酰水杨酸吗
Can't you put me back on 5ASA?
指不定有用
Maybe it'll work this time.
不太可能  我给你个处方
Not likely. I'm giving you a prescription.
价廉  物美
It's cheap, which is good,
因为保险公司不为这药买单
'cause your insurance company won't pay for it.
-香姻  -对  香烟
- Cogaritis?  - Cigarettes.
一天两次  一次一支
One twice a day. No more, no less.
研究表明吸烟
Studies have shown that cigarette smoking is
是控制肠炎
one of the most effective ways
最有效的方法之一
to control inflammatory bowel.
而且吸烟
Plus it's been well-established
能让你看上去更酷
that you'll look 30% cooler.
你是在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
吸烟让你更酷吗  是的
About the looking cooler? Yeah.
剩下的倒是实话
The rest is true.
不过吸烟不是会上瘾而且有害吗
Isn't it addictive and dangerous?
我开的药几乎
Pretty much all the drugs I prescribe
都是易上瘾且有害的
are addictive and dangerous
唯一的区别是
The only difference with this one
吸烟是完全合法的
is it's completely legal.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
我前面在和护士聊天
I was talking to the nurse.
埃森尼奥  你认识他吗
Arsenio. Do you know him?
-不认识  -他的手机可以拍照
- Not really. - He can take pictures with his phone.
真厉害
Cool.
实验室里那个女的也很有趣
That woman from the lab was interesting too.
她在成为护士之前学的是天体物理学
She studied astrophysics before becoming a nurse.
你知道的比我都多
You know this stuff better than I do.
我喜欢去了解他人
Well, I love to hear all about people.
你住在修道院里
You live in a monastery.
那是我为我们的主和社会服务的地方
It's where I serve our Lord and the world best.
我们的主  也许吧
Our Lord, maybe.
不过其他人也许觉得
The rest of the world, on the other hand,
扶贫济困更有意义  或是...
would probably get more out of feeding the homeless or...
或是治病救人吗
Healing the sick?
-的确是个例子  -你从小就想做医生吗
- As an example, yeah. - Did you always want to be a doctor?
是的  从小
Always.
你从小就想成为修女吗
You always want to be a nun
我六岁的时候父母就死了
My parents died when I was six.
我是被教堂开的收养所养大的
I was raised in a foster home run by the Church.
十八岁的时候  我去了修道院
When I was 18, I went to the monastery,
并且做了宣誓
where they let me take my vows.
我没有别的的生活  也从不想要
I've known no other life, and I haven't wanted to.
好的  修女  希望你躺着不要乱动
Okay, Sister, we need you to lie as still as possible.
如果害怕  可以告诉我们
If you get scared, just let us know.
正如约拿于鲸鱼腹中所言
As Jonah said from inside the whale,
"穷尽生之希望  唯主存于我心"
"When I lost all hope, I turned my thoughts to the Lord."
上帝与她同在
She's got God on her side.
我不相信上帝
I don't believe it God.
你不觉得这是不可知的吗
You're not even a little agnostic?
这里闻起来怪怪的  正常吗
Is it supposed to smell funny?
有人今早在里面吐了
Someone ralphed in there this morning.
清理过了  但...
We cleaned it up, but...
修女  这是正常的  再坚持几分钟
It's normal, Sister. I-it's just a few more minutes.
我相信有股更强大力量
I believe in a higher order,
控制着世间的一切
that can control what happens,
但不是什么被赋予人形的叫"上帝"的东西
but not one anthropomorphic entity called "God"
控制着我们的日常生活
that's concerned with the everyday workings of you and me.
除了我们的日常生活
What else is there to control
还有什么是需要被控制的呢
but the everyday workings of you and me?
你总想着你自己  福曼
It's always about you, Foreman.
你认为我该想什么呢  花鸟鱼虫吗
What are you talking about? The trees, the fish?
难道它们才应该觉得它们是一切的中心吗
Should they be the ones that think it's all about them?
奇斯  你呢  你相信上帝吗
What about you, Chase? You believe in God?
我相信奥古斯丁修女没有血管病变
I believe Sister Augustine has no vascular pathology.
说明不是变应性肉芽肿性血管炎
Which means no Churg Strauss.
也就意味着豪斯误诊了
Which means House made a mistake.
不  不一定  也可能是别的问题
No, not necessarily. It could be something else.
甲状腺毒症  或是类癌...
Thyrotoxicosis, or carcinoid...
你不信上帝
You don't believe in God,
不过却全心全意相信一个凡人吗
but you're willing to put complete faith in one man?
拜托  这味道...
Please...the smell.
快把她弄出来
Let's get her out of there.
我来了  修女
I'm coming, Sister.
哦  那气味
Oh, the smell.
让我觉得很难受
I'm gonna be sick, sick.
-没有什么味道  -噢  哦  天啊
- There's no smell. - Oh--oh, God!
噢  是耶稣  我看见耶稣了
Oh, it's Jesus. It's Jesus.
他是为我而来的
He's coming for me!
他用他的火把燃烧我
He's burning me with his touch!
给她用安定
Let's get her on some Ativan.
拜托
Please!
幻嗅  宗教性幻觉
Smells, religious visions,
脑叶肿胀的症状
symptomatic type of lobe swelling.
我们不能让她...
We don't... we don't want her to...
她在抽搐
She's seizing.
颌骨闭合
Jaw block.
帮我让她侧过身
Help me get her on her side.
-宗教性幻觉吗  -对
- Religious visions? - Yeah.
接下来将会是...
And next comes...
病人疱疹性脑炎测试呈阳性
Patient tested positive for herpetic encephalitis.
这说明什么呢
So what's that tell us?
她的免疫系统功能被严重抑制
Her immune systemis severely compromised.
我知道这个  强的松能抑制免疫系统
Oh, I know. Prednisone compromises the immune system.
不正是你用来治疗
Isn't that the medicine that
她根本没有的病的药吗
you gave her for that thing she doesn't have?
对...嗨
Yeah, the... hey.
这个问题真是不怀好意啊
I'm thinking that's a trick question.
她的免疫系统被严重破坏
Her immune system is severely compromised.
两剂量的强的松不会造成如此结果
Two doses of Prednisone wouldn't do that.
你是在根据症状的严重程度来判断病因吗
Are you hanging your diagnosis on an adverb?
十秒后  我会宣布
In 10 seconds, I'm going to announce
我在门诊给了她错误剂量的药
that I gave her the wrong dose in the clinic.
-你准备承认失误吗  -如果你离开这里的话
- You're gonna admit negligence? - Unless you leave the room.
如果你留下  就必须要作证了
If you stay, you'll have to testify.
5...4...3...2...
Five... four... three... two...
门诊的时候我喝得的酩酊大醉  闭着眼睛
So there I was in the clinic, drunk. I open the drawer,
打开抽屉  顺手拿了一支注射器...
close my eyes, take the first syringe I can find...
哪些疾病可以解释免疫系统的损害
So, what are the options for compromised immune system?
混合性结缔组织病
Mixed connective tissue disease.
还能解释她在用过强的松后的病情缓解
It'd explain why she was feeling better on the Prednisone.
你确定她的病情
Sure she was feeling better
在变得如此很严重之前缓解过吗
right up to the moment when it almost killed her.
不过这确实符合她的所有症状
On the other hand, it explains the symptoms.
双手肿胀  肺部问题
Swollen hands, pulmonary problems,
心脏问题  全符合
cardiac problems, it all fits.
-但他的抗核抗体检测是正常的  -再去验血
- Except her ANA was normal.  - So redraw the blood.
不过治疗方法是皮质类固醇  也就是强的松
But the treatment is corticosteroids, Prednisone.
因为脑炎  我们已经不能再用了
And we can't go there because of the encephalitis.
那就用调节免疫
Well, treat it with something that
别用抑制免疫的药物来治疗
modulates the immune system, but doesn't suppress it.
高压氧舱
Hyperbaric oxygen chamber.
治疗自身免疫性疾病
There's no protocol for putting
不允许使用高压氧舱
a patient in a high-pressure oxygen room
的治疗方案
to treat autoimmune problems.
噢  对  你们总是遵循规则
Oh, you people, always with the protocols.
让修女接受高压氧舱治疗
Prep the nun.
停掉强的松
And discontinue the Prednisone.
我既高兴又生气
I am both amused and annoyed that
你居然希望我不要和你一样固执
you think I should be less stubborn than you are.
还记得波克拉底氏誓言吗[关于医生道德的誓词]
You are aware of the Hippocratic Oath, right?
那个以"第一不作伤害"作开头
The one that starts "First, do nor harm,"
接着叙述禁止堕胎  引诱
and then goes on to tell us no abortions, no seductions,
和禁止切除奴隶
and definitely no cutting of those
身体部分的誓言吗
who labor beneath the stone?
对  我读过一次  印象不怎么深刻
Yeah, I took a read once, wasn't impressed.
高压仓治疗可能引起氧中毒
Hyperbaric treatments could cause oxygen toxicity,
造成肺部和眼睛的损伤
lung and eye damage
任何治疗都有风险
Every treatment has its dangers.
这就是为什么我们只在
Which is why we only treat if we're
确信病人需要治疗的时候才给予治疗
convinced the patient actually needs the treatment.
我很确信  但你没有
I'm convinced. You're not.
问题是  你能怎么办呢
The question is, what are you gonna do about it?
我周四下午三点有空  你有四号人选吗
I have an opening Thursday at 3:00. Do you have a fourth?
他好吗
Is he any good?
我马上打回给你好吗
Uh, can I call you right back? Okay.
什么事
What's up?
压力会使氧气进入你身体
The pressure will force the oxygen into your system,
使血液饱和
and saturate your blood.
这会增强白细胞活力
It will enhance white cell activity,
减轻炎症
reduce the inflammation.
这能治疗
And that will help with
混合性结缔组织病吗
this mixed connective tissue disease?
我们会做10次治疗
We'll be doing about 10 treatments,
然后重新评估
and then we'll reevaluate.
是强的松导致了抽搐  是吗
The last treatment with Prednisone caused the seizures, right?
豪斯医生有多大把握呢
How confident is Dr. House about this?
你对强的松的过激反应
That you reacted so strongly to the Prednisone let
说明你的免疫系统
us know that you had an underlying problem
存在潜在问题
with your immune system.
我想这勉强算是
Then I guess it was a blessing.
上帝的赐福
Of sorts.
你最喜欢哪只圣诞驯鹿  阿诺德护士
So who's your favorite reindeer, Nurse Arnold?
-鲁道夫  -我总觉得你会选维克森
- Rudolph. - I would have thought it was Vixen.
-你在暗示什么吗  -没有
- What are you implying? - Nothing.
但我在圣诞派对上看到你和迈尔斯医生
But I saw you at the Christmas party with Dr.Miles
贾根斯医生  克瑞安多护士在一起
and Dr. Jargons and Nurse Crandall.
我只是在跳舞
I was just doing some Christmas dancing.
这里是礼拜堂
This is a chapel.
是用来祈祷的
A house of prayer.
用来祈祷的  嗯
A house of prayer. Huh.
难怪这里信号好
Well, that explainsthe good reception.
并且没人
Also why nobody's ever here.
我需要和你谈谈  豪斯医生
I need to talk with you, Dr. House.
奥古斯汀修女相信一些不真实的东西
Sister Augustine believes in things that aren't real.
我以为这是做修女工作必备的素质
I thought that was a job requirement for you people.
别人都知道她以说谎博得同情
She's been known to lie to get sympathy.
她有忧郁症
She's a hypochondriac.
你是在提醒我
So you're warning me that
我在治疗根本不存在的疾病
I may be treating a non-existent ailment.
喉咙痛  关节痛
Sore throats, joint pains.
她总有些地方不舒服
There's always something wrong.
但从没原因
And there's never a reason for it.
修道院院长居然也相信她
Mother Superior plays right into it.
免去她的工作义务
Lets Augustine off work duties.
认为她脆弱  给与特别对待
Treating her as...fragile. Special.
你一定觉得气愤吧
That must make you angry.
确实让我不快
It bothers me.
但其实这也对奥古斯汀不好
It's not really in Augustine's best interest.
要一块吗
Want some?
我不应该拿
I shouldn't.
我猜你作为修女看护
I guess you gotta be good at
一定擅长看穿人心  对吗
reading people to be a good infirmarian, huh?
你之前表现出骄傲  愤怒  嫉妒  贪吃
So we got pride, anger, envy, gluttony.
你在两分钟之内犯了七宗罪中的四宗
That four out of seven deadly sins in under two minutes.
你们在破规矩上比赛破纪录吗
Do you people keep records of these things?
难道有天主教奥运会吗
Is there a Cath-lympics?
-他们说你是天才  -他们真喜欢瞎聊
- They say you have a gift.  - They like to talk.
你总把你的智慧藏起来
You hide behind your intelligence.
对  多愚蠢啊
Yeah, that's pretty stupid.
你总嬉皮笑脸是因为
And you make jokes because
你害怕对待事情太认真
you're afraid to take anything seriously.
如果太认真  它们对你便意味着什么
Because if you take things seriously, they matter.
如果意味着什么
And if they matter...
一旦出问题  我会受到伤害
Then when things go wrong, I get hurt.
-我不冷酷  我只是容易受伤  -我不了解你
- I'm not tough, I'm vulnerable.  - I barely know you.
我不知道我是不是对的  我希望我是
And I don't know if I'm right. I just hope I am.
因为如果不是
Because the alternative is,
你就真的和你看起来一样可怜了
you really are as miserable as you seem to be.
从你现在看我的眼神来看
You know, from the way you're looking at me right now,
你犯了第五宗罪
I'd say you just hit number five.
色欲
Lust.
布朗医生  我也爱你
Dr. Brown, I love you too.
你感觉怎样
How you feeling?
-有些虚弱  -那是因为氧气的原因
- A little weak. - That's from the oxygen.
我嘴巴很干
My mouth is dry.
好吧  嗯  我去帮你拿你的茶
Okay, well, uh, I'll get you some of your tea.
混合性结缔组织病吗
Mixed connective tissue disease?
她的抗核抗体几乎没有升高
Her ANA is barely elevated.
谢谢您视察我的工作
Well, thanks for checking upon her.
贴身照料我
Good to know you got my back.
氧饱和度下降到83
O2 sats down to 83.
肺部问题  呼吸问题
Pulmonary problems, breathing problems...
氧气引起的刺激很典型
Irritation from the oxygen is typical.
她入院时只有皮疹
She comes in with a rash,
你却治出了心脏骤停
and you put herinto cardiac arrest.
你永远都不会罢休是吧
That well just never runs dry, does it?
如果她没有任何潜在问题
If there was no underlying problem,
为什么她的心跳仍然过快
why is she still having the rapid heart rate?
也许是强的松
Maybe from the herpetic encephalitis
所引发的疱疹性脑炎引起的
caused by you giving her Prednisone.
她的反应是一个症状  我没有失误
Her reaction is a symptom, not an error.
总是有原因的  是吧
There's always an explanation, isn't there?
可以这么说
Yes, there is,
如果这个解释不通  我们会找别的
and if this one doesn't work, we'll find another.
不过没有一个是因为你犯错了
But never one involving you screwing up.
找一个符合所有线索的
One that fits all the facts.
我们显然意见不同
Look, we obviously have a difference of opinion,
没关系
and that's fine.
我今天做的无用功
I used up all the time I
已经够多的了
budgeted today for banging my head against a wall.
我将从一个医生的角度
I am gonna do you the biggest favor
来帮你一个大忙
one doctor can do for another.
我不会让你害死自己的病人
I am gonna stop you from killing your patient.
这病人不归你管了
You're off the case.
我们对症下药吧
We're gonna treat the symptoms.
不管其它的潜在病症了吗
Not the underlying condition?
没有什么潜在的病
There is no underlying condition.
她现在怎么样了
What's her status?
呼吸困难
The sister's breathing is labored.
应该是高压氧舱导致的肺炎
Pneumonitis from the hyperbaric chamber.
给她用40%的氧气
Put her on 40% oxygen
直到她血氧饱和度有所增加
until her O2 sats increase.
尿素酶和肌酐都在升高
BUN and creatinine's rising.
ALT和AST是正常值的两倍
ALT and AST twice the normal range.
可能是低血压导致的
Could be from the hypotensive episode.
继续跟进实验室检查的结果吧
Let's follow them with labs.
她入院时的疹子和关节痛仍未消失
She still has the rash and joint pain she came in with.
用非甾体抗炎药
Order a non-steroidal anti-inflammatory.
我们和豪斯医生一起鉴别诊断时
When we were looking at the differential diagnosis with Dr. House,
我们认为
we were considering...
我不想听豪斯医生的任何看法
I don't need to hear what Dr. House was considering.
这个女人的一切症状
All of this woman's symptoms
都可能是豪斯医生治疗的结果
can be traced to Dr. House's considerations.
好吧
Okay.
咱们赶紧让病人恢复健康
Let's just get this patient healthy.
我希望她能活着出去
I want her going out the front door and not the back.
嘿  我没有背叛他
Hey, it's not like I betrayed him.
卡迪最终肯定会发现
Cuddy would've found out
我们用了高压氧舱的
about the hyperbaric treatments eventually.
你做的是份内的事情
You did what you felt you had to.
在这还没待够吗
Can't get enough of this place, huh?
我来找听诊器
I came for my stethoscope.
我是不是不该纠结于你在那个
So I shouldn't read too much into the fact that you
放着肾上腺素注射器的抽屉里找听诊器
were looking for it in the drawer with the epinephrine syringes in it?
对  我是想洗脱我的嫌疑
Okay. Yeah. I'd like to cure my reputation.
好吧  我忘了你有多么
Oh, right, I forgot how much you care
在意别人的看法
about what people think.
让肠炎的病人抽烟
Prescribing cigarettes for inflammatory bowel?
会引发肺癌的
They cause lung cancer, you know.
你知道为什么乳腺癌  结直肠癌  前列腺癌
You know why they have ribbons for breast cancer,
都有代表它们的丝带[社会关爱组织标志]
colorectal cancer, prostate cancer,
而肺癌却没有吗
and not for lung cancer
颜色不够了吗
They...ran out of colors?
因为人们责备得肺癌的人
It's because people blame lung cancer patients.
抽烟  是他们自作自受
They smoke, they screwed up, they deserve to die.
肺癌的人都是死于内疚
The reason people die from lung cancer is guilt.
没错  内疚造成的伤害很大
Well, guilt does a lot of damage.
你说得很有道理
You said that with great significance.
你不是来这找你的听诊器
You're not here to find your stethoscope.
也不是来洗脱你的嫌疑
You're not here to clear your reputation.
你来这  是因为你也在怀疑
You're here because you're having doubts.
自己可能错了
You might've screwed off.
来这是为了确信我是对的
I'm here because if I'm right,
卡迪会害死那个病人的
Cuddy is killing that patient.
好吧
Okay.
但你要是错了呢
But if you're wrong?
-那她就救了她  -行
- Then she's saving her. - Fine.
你得仔细查看最近两天
You're gonna have to go through every record of
诊所每一个病人的病历
every patient who's been through this clinic in the last two days.
你还希望这些
And you're gonna have to hope
病历确实可信
that those records can be trusted.
顺便说一下  你的那些都不可信
Which, by the way, yours can't.
修女  这些药片
These pills'll help your
可以帮助你恢复肾功能
kidneys function a little better, Sister.
看看你的脉搏
Get your wrist.
怎么样
What's it at?
情况好吗
Is that good?
挺好的
It's fine.
奇斯医生  你不擅长撒谎
You're a lousy liar, Dr. Chase.
妈妈呼叫
Call Mom
不好意思  我得出去一趟
I have to get this. Excuse me.
我妈妈都死了十年了
My mother's been dead for ten years.
但她永远活在你心中
But she's always with you in spirit.
你知道那个修女的事吗
What do you know about the nun?
哪一个
Which one?
那个可爱的  我觉得她喜欢我
The cute one. I think she likes me.
当然是病的那个啊
The sick one, obviously.
她父母在她小时候就死了
Her parents died when she was a child.
之后她就一直在教堂里生活
And she's been with the Church ever since.
-她哪儿撒谎了  -为什么这么说
- What's she lying about?  - Why do you say that?
我从来都这么说
I always say that.
那个老修女认为
And the old nun thinks
生病的那个是个大骗子
the sick nun is a big, fat nun liar.
你很了解修女  你怎么看
You know nuns. What do you think?
我不了解修女
I don't know nuns.
你讨厌修女
You hate nuns.
你要不了解的话  是不会讨厌的
You can't hate someone if you don't know them.
了解纳粹吗  可能我就是讨厌她们
Know any Nazis? Maybe I hate them on principle.
关于好孩子是怎么变好的  我有个理论
I have a theory about what makes good boys good.
并不是什么道德觉悟
It's not because of some moral imperative.
好孩子对上帝心存畏惧
Good boys have the fear of God put into them.
天主教尤其擅长这种教育
Catholic Church specializes in that kind of training.
让好孩子们害怕上帝的惩罚
To make good boys afraid of divine retribution.
所以他们会对父母唯命是从
So they'll do what their daddies tell 'em.
比如说
Like, for example,
他们不希望自己的孩子去学医
going into medical school when it's the last thing they want to do.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我觉得如果她真的撒谎的话  院长会知道
I think if she did have a secret, her boss would know.
你们最近粉刷了或者买了新的地毯吗
Did you paint or put in new carpets recently?
没有
No.
她有可能接触到药品吗
Any way she could've got access to drugs?
我们的药都锁在医务室里
Well, we lock all our medications in the infirmary,
而且我们这也没有处方药
and we don't keep prescription drugs here.
为什么不直接问奥古斯丁修女呢
Why haven't you asked sister Augustine about these things directly?
我发现  如果你想
I found that when you want to know
真正了解一个人
the truth about someone,
一般最后才去问这个人
that someone is probably the last person you should ask.
你和尤凯瑞斯修女聊过了吗
And have you been speaking to Sister Eucharist?
她很快就出卖了她的同伴
She ratted out her fellow sister pretty quickly.
如果我是你  肯定让她回来重念修女学校
If I were you, I'd have her repeat a year of nun school.
修女并不是圣人
Becoming a nun doesn't make you a saint.
医生也并不能治百病
Becoming a doctor doesn't make you a healer.
虽然我们住在修道院
And just because we live in a monastery
大部分时间都在祈祷
and we spend most of our time in prayer
但我们的生活同样很有戏剧性
doesn't mean we don't find time for drama.
那病了的修女  有些什么戏份
So what is the sick one's drama?
奥古斯丁修女来我们这之前
Sister Augustine lived in Catholic foster care
一直住在天主教寄养机构
until she came to us.
要茶吗
Tea?
好
Sure.
你们都会撒谎吗
Do all of you lie?
这个策略不错
It's a good strategy.
谎言重复起来很简单
It's simpler when you tell the same lie.
但她并非一直都是个好的天主教徒
But she does not spend her entire life as a good Catholic.
她心脏骤停时
When she had a cardiac arrest,
我解开她的衬衫  做心肺复苏
I had to open her blouse to do CPR.
结果发现了两件事
And I learned two things.
修女也可以有傲人的胸部
Nuns can have nice breasts.
而且她肩膀上有纹身
And she has a tattoo on her shoulder.
是只臭鼬
Of a skunk.
可能那只臭鼬是约瑟夫的化身
Now, maybe this was the sacred skunk of Joseph,
但据我所知
but as far as I know,
天主教寄养机构里
Catholic foster care and monasteries
并没有纹身店
do not keep tattoo parlors in their refectories.
我们认为我们的生命
We consider that our life begins...
从我们许下誓言的那一刻才正式开始
... when we put on our habits and take our vows.
在此之前发生的一切
What happens before then...
和你无关  但和我有关
It's irrelevant to you. But it's relevant to me.
奥古斯丁修女
Sister Augustine went
六岁时去了天主教寄养机构
into foster care when she was six years old.
但十二岁时她离开了
But she left when she was 12.
她流落街头  染上了毒瘾
She lived on the streets, she got into drugs.
十五岁时  她怀孕了
When she was 15, she became pregnant.
她想自己流产
Tried to self-abort.
她的孩子没了  她也病了
She lost the child, she became ill.
她回来时  我们收留了她
We took her in when she came back.
如果这些和医学相关
If we had thought that it was medically relevant,
我们肯定会告诉你的
we would have told you.
确实无关
It's not.
这茶味道不错
This tea is delicious.
本地的吗
Local herbs?
用药后病人情况有变化吗
Any change with the medication?
变得更糟了  肺功能也在恶化
Yeah, she's getting worse. Lung functions deteriorating,
尿素酶和肌酐持续上升
BUN and creatinine continuing to rise.
病人发烧  疹子也在扩散
She's starting to run a fever, and the rash is spreading.
这样下去  她活不过圣诞
At this rate,she's not gonna make Christmas.
或许豪斯是对的
Maybe House was right.
或许确实有些潜在病症
Maybe there is an underlying
导致了这些症状
condition that explains the symptoms.
一些我们没考虑到的病
Something we haven't considered.
比如说
Like what?
可能是代谢紊乱
It could be a metabolic disorder.
-具体点  -可能是遗传病
- Specifically?  - Might be genetic.
再具体点
Specifically?
我只是说
I'm just saying that...
你只是说你觉得豪斯是对的
You're just saying you think House is right.
可能是对的
Might be right.
他当然可能是对的
Of course he might be right.
这还可能是上帝的旨意
It might be the hand of God at work.
你要没有确凿的证据
Don't say it's something else
就不要乱说
unless you've got something concrete to offer.
这是什么  毒芹吗
What's this? Hemlock?
这是我从一个医生的角度
I'm gonna do you the biggest favor
帮你最大的一个忙
one doctor can do for another.
来阻止你害死你的病人
I'm gonna stop you from killing your patient.
这是玄参茶
It's figwort tea.
很不错的提神饮料
Great for that little pick-me-up
我们早上常喝
we're all looking for in the morning.
增加肺活量
Opens the lungs,
升血压  还刺激心脏
increases the blood pressure, stimulates the heart.
不幸的是
Unfortunately,
只要注射0.1毫升的肾上腺素
if you then get injected with even 0.1cc of epinephrine,
就会造成心跳骤停
instant cardiac arrest.
不过  管他呢  味道挺不错的
Still, what the hell, it tastes great.
奥古斯丁修女她
Sister Augustine...
经常很虔诚地喝这个茶
...has been drinking it religiously, so to speak.
如果不考虑心脏问题的话
And if you take the cardiac arrest out of the equation...
其它所有的症状
all the rest of the symptoms can
都可以用长期严重过敏来解释
be explained by a severe long-term allergic reaction.
正如卡梅隆当初说的
Well, that's what Cameron said in the beginning.
没错  她是说过
Yes. She did.
做得好
Well done.
但你不能坚持自己的诊断
But your unwillingness to stick by your diagnosis
差点害死了这个女人
almost killed this woman.
多向福曼学学
Take a lesson from Foreman
如何坚持己见
and stand up for what you believe.
好了  让我们想想怎么救这个修女吧
Okay. Let's go figure out how to save a nun.
做也不对  不做也不对
Damned if you do, damned if you don't.
因为太久没有治疗
'Cause it's been untreated for so long,
这过敏从流眼泪
it's gone from a simple watery eyes,
喉咙痒
scratchy throat allergy
恶化到了能置人于死地的程度
to a whopping I'm-gonna-kick-your-ass allergy.
威胁到了她的免疫系统
Compromising her immune system,
让她无法自愈
diminishing her ability to heal,
还损害了她的很多器官
and breaking down her organ systems.
那过敏原是什么
So what's the source?
清洁皂
The dish soap.
不  她好几天没洗碗了
No, symptoms persisted days
症状还是没好转
after the dish washing episode.
应该是她在医院
It's gotta be something she's been exposed to here
和修道院都能接触到的东西
in the hospital, as well as the monastery.
会不会是那个茶
Well, what about the tea?
是它导致了心律不齐
It caused her arrhythmia.
有可能  但不能确定
Aah, could be, but it's not definitive.
我们可以做皮肤测试
We'll skin test for allergies.
暂时不行  她的过敏反应太强烈了
Not yet, she's too reactive.
所有东西都会呈阳性反应
She'll test positiveto everything.
我们得先让她稳定下来
We need to stabilize her,
把她和所有可能的过敏原隔离
isolate her from all possible allergens
让她的免疫系统休息一会
and give her system a rest.
把她搬到洁净室
Get her in the clean room.
行  然后让她依次接触
Okay, then we'll gradually
可能的过敏原  看她的反应如何
introduce allergens to see how she responds.
当她对某样东西过敏的时候
When she reacts to something,
我们就知道罪魁祸首究竟是什么了
we'll know that's what's killing her.
好了  没有电视  也没有书
There you go. No television, no books.
连圣经也不行吗
Not even my Bible?
恐怕不行
I'm afraid not.
这个房间里的空气和水都是过滤了的
This room has filtered air, filtered water.
连床单都是丝绸的
You even have silk sheets.
不会引起过敏的被单
Very decadent and hypoallergenic.
你在这里会好起来的
You should be feeling better here.
我们过一会回来复查
We'll be back to check on you in a little while.
其它的修女们能进来和我一起祈祷吗
Can the other sisters come in and pray with me?
最好不要有任何的拜访者
It'd be better if you don't have any visitors.
一旦隔绝了你的过敏原
Once we isolate what's causing your allergy,
我们大家都可以放松了
then we can be a little more relax.
我可以和你一起祈祷
I-I can pray with you.
我不想死
I don't want to die.
为什么上帝要抛弃我
Why has He left me?
当我还在神学院的时候
I was in seminary school.
他们问我们最喜欢圣经里的哪个段落
They asked us once what our favorite passage was.
我选择了彼得前书的第一章第七节
I chose First Peter 1:7.
一切都只是在测试你的信仰
"These trials only test your faith."
试其是否坚定且纯粹
"To see whether or not it is strong and pure."
你在经历试炼
"Your faith is being tested."
就如同用火萃取真金一般
"As fire tests gold and purifies it."
你的信仰对于上帝来说
"And your faith is far more precious.
比金子更宝贵
To the Lord than mere gold."
在经历之后
"So if your faith remains strong.”
信仰依然忠贞
"After being tested,
会带给你赞美与荣光
it will bring you much praise and glory and honor"
那一日  主  再临人间
"On the day of His return."
上帝没有抛弃你
He hasn't left you.
能让你知道上帝
The only thing in the way
存在的唯一方法就是恐惧
of you knowing He's there is your fear.
你要做出选择  诚心或恐惧
You have a choice. Faith or fear.
这就是考验
That's the test.
选择诚心并不意味着我不会死
Choosing faith doesn't mean I won't die.
但是会影响到你对死的感知
But it will affect how you will experience your death.
还有你的余生
And therefore your life.
这是你的选择
It's up to you.
为什么你要离开神学院
Why did you leave seminary school?
那个测试
That test...
你通过了  而我没有
...you passed, I didn't.
有变化的话我们会通知你的
We'll call you if anything changes.
她会好起来的吧
Will she be all right?
只要她不暴露在任何加剧她过敏的东西下
As long as she's not exposed to anything that can aggravate her allergy,
她会好的
she'll be fine.
这里需要帮忙
Need some help in here.
别管什么程序了  她正在过敏性休克
Screw the procedure. She's in anaphylactic shock.
不可能  他在隔离间里
No way, she's in the damn clean room!
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
快进来
Get in here!
0.1毫升肾上腺素
Point-one cc of epi.
我们必须插管
We've got to intubate.
我拿到了  拿上急救袋
I got it. Get the ambu bag.
插好了
I'm in.
呼吸稳定
Breathing stabilized.
这是隔离间
It's a clean room.
在隔离间里怎么能过敏呢
How do you get an allergic reaction in a clean room?
可能是因为IV的防腐剂
Maybe it was the preservatives in the IV.
查查看
Checked that.
-乳胶管呢  -也查一查
- Latex tubing?  - Checked that.
每样东西都查一查
Checked everything.
也可能是肥大细胞白血病
Well, it could be mast cell leukemia.
也可以引起过敏
It can cause anaphylaxis.
我们验过血了
We checked the blood levels.
不是嗜曙红细胞过多也不是特发性过敏症
And it's not eosinophilia or idiopathic anaphylaxis.
可能是主的意愿
Maybe it's just divine will.
但非我的意愿
It's not my will.
你应该知道
You do realize,
如果你对全局的看法是错误的话
if you're wrong... about the big picture, that is...
你会发火的  是吗
you're going to burn, right?
那你想我怎么样  接受它  放弃它
What do you want me to do? Just accept it, pack it in?
没错  我想要你接受
Yeah, I want you to accept
有些病人会毫无原因地死亡
that sometimes patients die against all reason.
有时候也会突然之间好转
And sometimes they get better against all reason.
这不可能的  只是我们不知道原因而已
No, they don't. We just don't know the reason.
我认为修女们会同意你的观点的
I think the nuns would agree with you on that.
我只是想告诉你
I just wanted to say that
你已经尽力了
I know you did everything you could.
我不需要由来你认同我的工作
I don't need verification from you to know that I'm doing my job well.
那是你的问题  不是我的
That's your problem, not mine.
我只是好心
I was just being nice.
好吧  你不用总是这么做的
Yeah, well, you don't need to always do that.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
奥古斯丁修女已经能正常呼吸了
Sister Augustine's been extubated.
很好
Good.
她不听劝阻执意要出院
She's requested to check out against medical advice.
她想回修道院
She wants to go back to the monastery.
好吧  叫她走吧
Well, talk her out of it.
我认为我不应该同意她走
I think I may have talked her into it.
本周的住院费都交过了
Room's paid up for the rest of the week.
最好还是多住几天吧
Might as well stick around.
这个病是对我信仰的考验
This illness is a test of my faith.
如果上帝想我死
If it's his will to take me,
那我在哪里死都一样的
it doesn't matter where I am.
我能欣然接受的
I can accept that.
有人会相信你说的东西吗
Does anybody believe anything you say?
你不是在欣然接受
You're not accepting.
你是在逃避
You're running away.
你一直都这么干
Just like you always do.
你为了过平常人的生活从修道院里跑出去
You ran away from the monastery to get laid.
你觉得平常人的生活没意思了
You ran away from the real world
又跑回修道院里去了
when getting laid didn't work out so good.
今时不同往日  别逃避了
Now things aren't working out again, so off you go.
为什么让你信奉上帝那么难呢
Why is it so difficult for you to believe in God?
困难的原因
What I have difficulty with
是因为自信
is the whole concept of belief.
信仰不是基于逻辑和经验的
Faith isn't based on logic and experience.
我每天都能感觉到上帝的存在
I experience God on a daily basis.
还有身边生命的奇迹
And the miracle of life all around.
新生命的奇迹
The miracle of birth.
爱情的奇迹
The miracle of love.
上帝与我常在
He is always with me.
对于先天不足的婴儿来说  奇迹在哪呢
Where is the miracle in delivering a crack-addicted baby?
她的母亲放弃了她
And watching her mother abandon her
因为她的妈妈想要正常的孩子
'cause she needs another score.
爱的奇迹
Miracle of love.
被所爱的人杀的机率大大超过
You are over twice as likely to be killed
被陌生人杀的机率
by the person you love than by a stranger.
你是想叫我放弃信仰吗
Are you trying to talk me out of my faith?
死后  你的灵魂里
You can have all the faith you want
你爱信什么信什么
in spirits and the afterlife.
还有天堂和地狱里
And heaven and hell.
但当你还在这个世界的时候  别傻了
But when it comes to this world, don't be an idiot.
你当然可以和我说
'Cause you can tell me that you
你是靠对上帝的信仰过活
put your faith in God to get you through the day.
但当你过马路的时候
But when it comes time to cross the road,
你还是会看看有没有车
I know you look both ways.
我不相信他会搭救我
I don't believe he is inside me and is going to save me.
我相信不管我生或死他都与我同在
I believe He is inside me whether I live or die.
那你最好还是活着
Then you might as well live.
押我比押上帝更容易赢
You got a better shot betting on me than on Him.
在我15岁的时候
When I was 15,
我采取了所有我知道的避孕方法
I was on every kind of birth control known to man.
但我还是怀孕了
And I still got pregnant.
我恨上帝
I blamed God.
恨他毁了我的生活
I hated Him for ruining my life.
但我意识到
But then I realized something.
你不能对上帝生气的同时也信奉着上帝
You can't be angry with God  and not believe in Him at the same time.
没人可以
No one can.
你也不例外  豪斯医生
Not even you, Dr. House.
怎样了
How'd it go?
她虔诚地信奉着上帝
She has God inside her.
一定对肿瘤治疗很有帮助
Would've been easier to deal with a tumor.
可能她对上帝过敏
Maybe she's allergic to God.
我们检查过她所有能引起她过敏的地方
We've looked everywhere for an allergen that could be causing this reaction
除了一个地方
except one place.
体内
Inside her.
病史里她没有做过手术啊
On her medical history, she didn't mention any surgery.
有过一次
She had one.
我们能拿到记录吗
Can we get her records?
是在什么医院做的手术
What hospital was it at?
她没有在医院里做手术
She didn't have it at a hospital.
给她做个全身检查
Order a full body scan.
她要是拒绝怎么办
What if she refuses?
告诉她我在寻找奇迹
Tell her I'm looking for a miracle.
没有穿孔  也没有填充物
No piercings. No fillings.
手臂里也没有外科手术针
No surgical pins in the arm.
-没有植入物  -相当干净了
- No implants. - It's clean as a whistle.
豪斯到底在找什么
What's House looking for?
那是什么东西
What is that?
不知道
Don't know.
锁定它  获取三维立体图
Lock on it. Get a 3-D representation.
噢  天啊
Oh, my God.
铜环
The copper cross.
80年代用的避孕手段
A form of birth control pulled off the market in the '80s.
所以她对铜过敏
So she's allergic to copper?
很罕见  但是就是这样
Rare, but it happens.
难道她不知道她有宫内节育器吗
Didn't she know she had an IUD?
她流产过
She had an abortion.
宫内节育器一定是脱落了
IUD must have been left in,
埋入在子宫内膜组织上
embedded in the endometrial tissue
所以谁都没有发现
where it couldn't be detected.
所以我们要做的只是移除宫内节育器
So all we have to do is remove the IUD.
你就会好起来的了
Then the symptoms should subside.
我15岁的时候就上了这个节育器
I got this IUD when I was 15.
都有20多年了
I-it's been more than 20 years.
持续地暴露在低过敏症状中
prolonged exposure to an allergen with minimal symptoms.
但有些时候
But at some point,
只需要一次接触就会全面爆发
all it takes is one last contact to cause a full-blown reaction.
就像充满气的气球
It's like a balloon filled with air.
再吹一口气就会爆炸了
One last breath, it explodes.
我第一次出现疹子
The first time I got the rash
是在我洗铜制的炊具的时候
was when I was washing the copper cookware.
你之后所有的并发症
And all your subsequent
都是由于你吃了那个炊具做出来的食物
symptoms came from ingesting food prepared in it.
豪斯医生发现了他的奇迹
Dr. House found his miracle.
他不会这样说的
I doubt he'll interpret it that way.
你告诉了我你最喜欢的节选
You told me your favorite passage.
你想知道我的吗
Would you like to hear mine?
高兴地欢庆吧
"Celebrate and be glad."
因为你的兄弟死而复生
"Because your brother was dead and is alive again."
归回父家歌
The prodigal son.
当你准备好的时候他会等着你的
He'll be waiting for you when you're ready.
我们给你安排明天的手术
We'll schedule your surgery for tomorrow.
第六地狱
The sixth circle of hell.
被限于一隅方寸
Confined in a sweat box with a bloody nose,
到处都是血腥味
and all the tissues are soggy.
那应该是第七地狱吧
I think that's the seventh.
不是  第七地狱是
No, the seventh is...
天啊  你在派对上一定很好玩
God, you must be fun at parties.
我们都知道那个理论的缺陷
I think we both know the flaw in that theory.
-那个修女怎样了  -心率正常
- How's the sister? - Heart rate is normal,
肾功能正常
kidney is functioning.
知道为什么吗
You know how it is with nuns,
拿走了宫内节育器后  一切都好了
you take out their IUDs, they just bounce right back.
-很好  -早说过我没有搞砸
- Great. - Told you I didn't screw up.
你搞砸了
You screwed up.
我给她0.1毫升的肾上腺素
I gave her point-one cc of epinephrine.
是的  如果卡迪没有把你踢出这个病例的话
Yeah, and if Cuddy hadn't taken you off the case,
你可能杀了她了
you would've killed her.
想来参加圣诞晚宴吗
You wanna come over for Christmas dinner?
你是犹太人
You're Jewish.
是的  光明节晚宴  你介意些什么
Yeah, Hanukkah dinner. Wh-what do you care?
食物不对口还是人
It's food, it's people.
不了  谢谢
No thanks.
或许我会去你那里的
Maybe I'll come to your place.
你妻子不介意一个人过圣诞节吗
Your wife doesn't mind being alone at Christmas?
我是个医生  她习惯一个人了
I'm a doctor, she's used to being alone.
-我不想谈论这个  -我也不想
- I don't want to talk about it. - Neither do I.
做的不错啊  修女的病例
You did good. With the nun.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
圣诞快乐  豪斯医生
Merry Christmas, Dr. House.
还有威尔森医生
Dr. Wilson.
晚安
Good night.
真贴心
That was sweet.